AYUSHI BATWARA

(510) 737-9391 • ayushi.batwara@berkeley.edu • linkedin.com/in/ayushibatwara • github.com/ayushib4

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Finding ways to use software to make a big impact. Interning at big tech, bootstrapping a startup, and researching for the government. Previously created a simulation to teach 1.2M+ students about clinical disparities, won 5+ national hackathons.

Languages: Python • Java • JavaScript • SQL • HTML • CSS

Tools/Frameworks/Libraries: FastAPI • Git • AWS • Boto3 • React • Swagger • Docker • NumPy • Pandas

EDUCATION AND COURSEWORK

UC Berkeley – Management, Entrepreneurship, and Technology (M.E.T.) Program

Expected May 2024

Dual Degree: B.S. Electrical Engineering and Computer Sciences, B.S. Business Administration; GPA: 3.93

Awards: Scott Herst M.E.T. Fellow, Cal Alumni Association (CAA) Leadership Award Scholar

Relevant Coursework: Designing Information Devices and Systems • Data Structures • Discrete Math and Probability Theory

Eastlake High School

Sep 2018 – Jun 2021

Unweighted GPA: 4.0; President of National Computer Science Honors Society, Vice President of Math Honors Society

EXPERIENCE

Vanta, San Francisco, CA

Dell Technologies, Seattle, WA

Incoming Jun 2023 – Jun 2022 – Aug 2022

Software Engineer Intern

- Designed and developed 3 public-facing APIs to address customer use-cases for a multi-cloud storage product in AWS: 1) inventory management, 2) cost management, 3) compliance and resource configuration
- Development: FastAPI, Boto3 API, native AWS services; Documentation: Swagger for OpenAPI specifications per endpoint
- Participated in Dell's Internal Hackathon and created an internal "Discover Intern" tool with Python & Tkinter library

Bellweather, Berkeley, CA

Jan 2022 - Present

Co-Founder and Machine Learning Lead

- Co-founder of a Berkeley SkyDeck-backed startup that won 2nd place at Apple x UCSF's iHackHealth Hackathon
- Developing a random forest ML model (99.6% accuracy) to predict an individual's relative risk in extreme climate conditions across database of 10k+ patients based on health data captured from Apple Health, IBM Weather, EHRs, clinical risks

Boston Public Health Commission, Boston, MA

Jun 2022 – Present

ML Research Intern

• Creating "digital twin pairs" for counties throughout the United States using a machine learning pipeline (CNNs, KNN, Regression) based on satellite imagery data, chronic disease, health system access, demographics, and deprivation to allow public health departments to collaborate with departments across the country most similar to them

Projects & Hackathons

Jan 2020 - Present

Decoded Hacks and Hack Kosice Digital – "COVID-PRO Tips"

- Winning project (1/27 teams) developed interactive website for COVID-19 with up-to-date data/analytics, including:
 - Medication interaction checker built on National Library of Medicine's RxNav API Services
 - Visual representation of current cases and statistics globally on an interactive map
 - o Counter that helps users estimate quantity of household supplies/necessities needed to stay in quarantine
- Frontend Bootstrap, Backend Node.js, ExpressJS, AWS EC2, Languages JavaScript, HTML, CSS

Incentivizing Health Hackathon – "1Upstream Health"

• <u>Winning project</u> (1/10 teams) – an interactive, evidence-based health education program that integrates with multiple platforms, utilizing gamification to activate young people to take ownership of their own health

LA Hacks 2021 - "Moodacado"

- <u>Project</u> that uses an ML model to visualize mood based on analysis of Spotify listening history
- Frontend React, Backend Flask, ExpressJS, PostgreSQL instance on Google Cloud, ML Model scikit-learn, NumPy, pandas

LEADERSHIP AND COMMUNITY IMPACT

Machine Learning at Berkeley (ML@B), Berkeley, CA

Jan 2022 - Present

Researcher & Education Committee Officer

- Club dedicated to fostering a vibrant machine learning community through industry consulting, research, and education
- Developing a reinforcement learning module to teach during the New Member Education Program

Washington HOSA – Future Health Professionals, Spokane, WA

Mar 2020 - Mar 2021

Washington State Secretary – elected by 180+ chapters and 3000+ members

- Initiated statewide COVID-19 Chapter Challenges program to support pandemic relief efforts; engaged 45+ chapters in WA
- Executed 2 virtual state conferences, redesigned website, spearheaded media outreach effort, created executive mentorship series for local chapters to engage with alumni/professionals, and advocated to WA State Legislature for CTE funding